Noe E. Leiva

6622 Tulip Tree Dr, Murfreesboro, TN 37128 (714) 585-9160 <u>Leiva.e.noe@gmail.com</u> https://www.linkedin.com/in/NoeLeivaDeveloper

KEY SKILLS / SKILL LEVELS:

- SQL / Advance
- SQL Language Stored Procedures / Advance
- C++, C#, Java / Advance
- JavaScript, CSS, HTML / Intermediate
- BOOMI Integration Solution / Intermediate
- Microsoft SQL Server Management Studio / Advance
- MS Visual Studios/ Advance

- Salesforce / Intermediate
- Truckmate / Intermediate
- Project Management / Intermediate
- Tableau / Intermediate
- SSIS and SSRS / Advance
- SQL Data warehouse / Intermediate
- ASP.NET MVC / Advance
- React, Node JS, Express, AJAX / Intermediate
- Source Tree, Stash, Git / Intermediate

EDUCATION (In progress *):

Vanderbilt University Coding Boot Camp (September Graduation)	2020*
National University Master of Science, Computer Science, Software Engineering Specialization	2017
Tableau Fundamentals	2015
University of California Riverside Bachelors of Arts, Economics	2013
Honors Society Member	2013
EDI Academy EDI Fundamentals and Best Practices Training Course	2009

CAREER SUMMARY:

Over 10 years of IT experience. Skills include business and operations development, creative problem solving; above all, translating business requirements into working applications.

The ability to adapt and learn fast has given me the opportunity to succeed where my years of experience has come short. My dedication and hard work has giving me the opportunity to always deliver a project successfully. Highlighting my ability to work well with our business team and translate requirements into well-thought-out applications that follow appropriate software development practices.

Overall, 8+ years of experience working with several SQL products, which include MySQL and Microsoft SQL Server. Building T-SQL scripts and ETL automated jobs. Advanced knowledge in Object Oriented Software development practices. This includes but not limited to, advance knowledge in C#, C++, Java, JavaScript, SQL languages to name a few. Extensive experience building APIs and exchanging data between different trading partners and other open source data connections; exchanging files such as EDI, XML, JSON, HL7.

Now, for the past 2 years developed and troubleshoot ETL processes that comprised of complex SQL scripts and C# code. Using multi-thread practices, increased the speed of many newly and already implemented applications by over 40%. At the same time, in the afternoons focused on integrating my extensive back-end experience with best practices learned and put in practice during my master's program the integration of user interfaces; building ASP.NET and REACT applications, incorporating API controllers with server and database models. Subsequently, publishing the applications to GitPages, Netlify, and Heroku.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Cigna Health Spring -Nashville, TN

01/2019-Present

Application Development Advisor

- My role continues to be the same as an Application Development Senior Specialist; however, I have more control now. Communicating with our business partners directly and making the final decision to our development approach and implementation.
- Migrated SSIS packages to use configuration files.
- Implemented Stash for our Risk Assessment team to manage and control our code through Source Control best practices.

Cigna Health Spring -Nashville, TN

04/2018-01/2019

App Development Sr. Specialist

- Plan and develop system applications and products based on both user needs and industry standards. Actively participating through all technical phases of the project in Agile and Operational Development environments through best practices and company change control processes.
- Support the EDI team by building applications and reports that identify the gaps and improvement routes in both our Claim and Encounter submission processing methods and CMS response messages.
- SSIS packages that reconcile all outbound claims with inbound messages from CMS. Incorporating both C# and SQL best practices and methodologies.
- SSRS reports capable to drill-through from a high-level view of volume to a detail understanding of the metrics and responses.
- Troubleshoot, maintain, and develop application and systems solutions for all business products and regular
 operational processes. Providing and creating testing and implementing application and systems product
 technical changes as needed.

Inland Empire Health Plan – Rancho Cucamonga, CA

04/2017-04/2018

Developer

- Support the EDI team by building reports in a timely manner to identity gaps and improvement routes in our Claim and Encounter processing methods. SSRS reports that entail high level volume, which have the functionality to drill-through for a more detail view.
- Reconcile the EDI volume by building SSIS packages, SQL Stored Procedures, and SSRS reports to identify the volume of Claims and Encounters adjudicated against the data sent out to the regulatory bodies. Moving into production jobs such as The Manifest Load and Encounter Reconciliation Report automated jobs to name a few.
- Facilitate the processing of the current Claims to Encounter system by building software applications in C# to clean up already processed files and search for EDI 837 files to process.
- Taking part in the BizTalk training to begin helping the development team to improve and maintain the application to adjudicate all EDI Claim and Encounter files.
- Took part in the first wave of training on the new Electronic Data Interchange Management System (EDIMS) for CORE. Spearheading the review process of the business rules implemented to validate the inbound EDI volume. At the same time, bringing into light and training team members on the new database structures and EDIMS application data handling capabilities.
- Built and automated the C# EDI Parser to support and balance the Outbound EDI volume to the regulatory bodies. Ensuring all outbound data transmitted to our trading partners was accounted for and reconciled with the responses received from them.

• Troubleshoot SQL applications currently in production with IEHP. Familiarizing with all our SQL servers, SSIS packages, and SQL stored procedures. Updating some outdated development efforts with new and improved SQL processing practices. Resolving current business user's needs and troubles they come across.

Health Essentials – Santa Ana, CA

06/2015 - 01/2016

Database and System Analyst

- Initially joined the team as an EDI Analyst. Bringing in-house from the offshore team all the EDI ETL workflows (SSIS packages) that processed and managed the trading partner's enrollment files. SSIS packages were composed of several SQL stored procedures, which I managed and updated to match the business needs.
- Oversaw the TOC automated process by implementing new changes and ensuring all new entries were applied accordingly to our business rules. These TOCs were compared against our database using flags and qualifiers stored in tables and matched using SQL Stored Procedures, Triggers and Functions.
- Administered the internal Aprima (EMR) support service. Ensuring access and roles were successfully implemented in the EMR tool.
- Supervised and Developed other automated services and new automation requests (SSIS). Creating new SQL stored procedures and SSIS packages to download the data from different partners' sites (FTP, SFTP, Portal).
- Maintained and Administered the Tableau reporting tool. Ensuring the reports in production ran successfully and met the customer's needs. Also, implemented new dashboards that included Parameters and direct connectivity to our reporting database using the different views the team and I created for our customers.
- Operated all database analytic requests for my department implementing SSRS packages against our SQL database. Using and creating the different tables and views in our database, monitored already in production reports and generated new reports for the upper management in my team.

Daylight Transport - Long Beach, CA

07/2013 -06/2015

Application Developer

- Managed the Gentran EDI tool during the life of the engine by ensuring all EDI transactions were transmitted to
 our trading partners successfully. Implemented new validation scripts to the EDI maps to accommodate our
 partner's needs.
- Migrated our EDI services out of Gentran to the BOOMI solution. During the migration, out of the Gentran tool,
 I had the opportunity to learn the BOOMI Integration Software. This powerful tool allowed me to migrate over
 40 EDI processes to its system and implement an additional 60 new trading partner connections, which initiated
 my learning experience with SQL Language stored procedures.
- Created and updated several SQL stored procedure to troubleshoot numerous Truckmate failures that limited our ability to communicate with our agents via EDI.
- Worked with the following transaction sets: Load Tender/Pickup Notification (204), Electronic Freight Bills (210), Shipment Status Messages (214), Remittance Advise (820), XML, and Flat File.
- Worked directly in the integration of Intelligent Freight Transportation Systems in our loading/unloading trucking locations. These jobs included BOOMI ETL processes that called several SQL Stored Procedures.